Abraham: The main form of unethical
conduct we think about within
cyber security is hacking, but
there are other forms of unethical
conduct that may take place.
It may involve deliberately copying
information and data to use or supply
to others for unethical activities.
Nicole: Unethical behaviour can
involve sabotage, disclosing or
misusing confidential information or
maliciously injuring the reputation or
prospects of an individual or business.
Let’s look at this in
a little more detail.
Abraham: Sabotage- is rather an
obvious form of unethical conduct
and this can be seen when an employee
intentionally damages a system.
This may be for spite or to show that they
can fix an ‘existing’ problem to showcase
their skills or gain a ‘bug bounty’.
This may also be done by a disgruntled
employee who wants to get their
own back if they have an axe to
grind or have lost their job.
Nicole: Disclosing of misusing
confidential information- cyber
security professional have access to
a great deal of personal confidential
data and may feel that it might be
worth something to pass it on to
someone else or use it for blackmail.
Abraham: Maliciously injuring
the reputation or prospects
of an individual or business.
Maliciously spreading information
or images can seriously damage the
reputation of a colleague or business.
Cyber security professionals are in a
trusted role having access to confidential
data and should never use this against
someone as this is totally unethical.
Nicole: But unethical conduct doesn’t
always have to be on a large scale it can
also be something as simple as leaving
a 'post it' around with log in details
for anyone to access a computer system.
Abraham: It may be thoughtless or show
a lack of judgement, but it can lead
to so much more as this can open a
system up to unethical security issues.
Nicole: It’s also important to remember
that cyber security professionals are
highly trusted members of staff who have
a great deal of access to important,
sensitive and highly confidential data.
They should never use and abuse this
high level of access and trust placed
in them by displaying unethical conduct.